<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alireza Baloochi</title>
    <link>https://baloochi.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alireza Baloochi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baloochi.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Web 3</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2022/05/web-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2022/05/web-3/</guid>
      <description>So a lot of attention and advertisment is going towards web 3, I will show a small history of previous revisions of the web, a bit of explanation and my opinion towards it.
Revisions: Web 1.0 The first ever web revision that consisted of static websites, for example news websites, company websites, personal websites (like the one here). Only a single person or entity had control over the data, to update or create new pages or data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFTs are horrible</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2022/02/nfts-are-horrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2022/02/nfts-are-horrible/</guid>
      <description>I believe the NFT society would hate me but considering that twitter and YouTube are trying to enter this space, it&amp;rsquo;s worth to discuss it.
You can see a 2 hour video made by Folding Ideas about the topic which I strongly recommend, called Line Goes Up – The Problem With NFTs
Since the text is too long I will split it up to different sections.
Morality The whole concept of NFTs are buying something worthless and convincing someone to buy it at a higher price, the act itself carries 0 benefits (If not harm) for anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress Weaknesses</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2021/10/wordpress-weaknesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2021/10/wordpress-weaknesses/</guid>
      <description>After dealing with wordpress for 3 months, I come down to realize how crappy it is, a great example on what a project can become without a proper goal and heavy reliance on 3rd party code.
Free? (Not quite) Wordpress is free but it costs something more than money, time.
Even not considering the fact that most of the extensions will constantly bug you to buy their paid version. There is no standard for themes, or extensions or what sort of path they should follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Code-in</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2019/12/google-code-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2019/12/google-code-in/</guid>
      <description>The Journey It goes back all the way in November when Fedora Project tweeted that they need some Mentors for Google Code-in. Initially I didn&amp;rsquo;t knew what it was but after a simple search it was clear that it was a competition ran by Google.
So Google provided all the backend and platform for open source organizations, which mentors of each org then creates tasks in the system, which then the student solves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robocup Asia-Pacific @ Dubai</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</guid>
      <description>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects. The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/about/</guid>
      <description>My Full CV: 📃 Curriculum Vitae.
If you wish to contact me, you can send a message on Telegram.
Works:  Mentor at Google Code-in 2019 System Administrator at Tehran Internet Co. Exhibitor at Dubai Knowledge and Human Development Authority Ranked 5th in the National Cyber Olympiad Fedora Project Contributor Certified Online Tutor and E-lecture Designer by HBMSU Fedora Open source Project Contributor Dubai Young City Makers participant  Interests:  Swimming &amp;amp; biking Writing (Essay, Documentation) Coding &amp;amp; Designing Photography  Languages:  Persian (Native) English (Fluent) Arabic (Familiar) German (Familiar)  You can find more info about me in my Linkedin, I post updates there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photographs</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/photographs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/photographs/</guid>
      <description>Here you can see my shots, for obvious reasons they are heavily compressed here. 
Full Image gallery in 500px Tehran - Chitgar Park FiruzKuh - Zarindasht FiruzKuh - HableRud Dubai - DubaiMall</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
