<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Alireza Baloochi</title>
        <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Alireza Baloochi</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://baloochi.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Web 3</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2022/05/web-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2022/05/web-3/</guid>
            <description>So a lot of attention and advertisment is going towards web 3, I will show a small history of previous revisions of the web, a bit of explanation and my opinion towards it.
Revisions: Web 1.0 The first ever web revision that consisted of static websites, for example news websites, company websites, personal websites (like the one here). Only a single person or entity had control over the data, to update or create new pages or data.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So a lot of attention and advertisment is going towards web 3, I will show a small history of previous revisions of the web, a bit of explanation and my opinion towards it.</p>
<h3 id="revisions">Revisions:</h3>
<h4 id="web-10">Web 1.0</h4>
<p>The first ever web revision that consisted of static websites, for example news websites, company websites, personal websites (like the one here). Only a single person or entity had control over the data, to update or create new pages or data.</p>
<p><img src="/img/photo/web1.jpg" alt="Web 1.0"></p>
<h4 id="web-20">Web 2.0</h4>
<p>The current revision, this is were all the social media/blogs/online forms are. The site creator is not the only one controlling the data, users also generate content and participate in most parts of it, they can report other users in case of violation to even remove something. The catch is you are still bound to company&rsquo;s privacy policy, rules and other status while you are on the website, so there is not a 100% guaranteed freedom.</p>
<p><img src="/img/photo/twitter.jpg" alt="Web 2.0"></p>
<h3 id="the-elephant-in-the-room-web-30">The elephant in the room: Web 3.0</h3>
<p>This is were all the hype is directed towards. The best example to this are NFTs, the web 3 characteristics are the following:</p>
<h4 id="they-run-on-the-blockchain">They run on the blockchain:</h4>
<p>Perhaps you are already familiar with this, they are almost non-hackable, very energy intensive and <em>non reversible</em> in case of any wrong input data (you can&rsquo;t even edit your tweets anyway), considering the methods of conversation or payment we already have is very safe and 90% of the errors are human made. (oh I tyoed the wrong Iban, I didn&rsquo;t spell the name right and so on&hellip;) the last bit can be problamatic.</p>
<h4 id="there-are-not-bound-to-any-rules-or-very-minimal-rules">There are not bound to any rules or very minimal rules:</h4>
<p>Right now you can create an NFT of anything, even copyrighted media. You might not be able to sell it though. (Hence the <em>minimal</em> rules)</p>
<h4 id="the-data-can-travel-between-multiple-platforms">The data can travel between multiple platforms.</h4>
<p>We already have this: E-mail! , you can send and receive emails from gmail, outlook, hotmail, mail.de etc&hellip; With web 3.0 you can easily move contents to other places. The multi-platform support we have today is through companies having contracts with each other (like sign-in with google) or some pre-determined standard (E-mail).</p>
<h4 id="imporoved-privacy">imporoved privacy</h4>
<p>Due to the <em>blockchain</em>. A bit arguable as username/password is all you need to lose. most platforms today are very safe while transmitting/storing data. 90% of the attacks happen on the user when they give away their passwords, or their passwords get phished by hackers. A protective measure is already made: 2 Factor Authentication.</p>
<h3 id="my-opinion">My Opinion</h3>
<p>You can see for the most benefits mentioned there are already some very good solutions in place, but is web 3.0 really better?
The answer is No (With few key exceptions)
Most of the people hyping web3 are from 2 categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Money makers</li>
<li>Enthusiasts</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Let&rsquo;s start with the first category:</strong>
Usually they are the people who will take money from investors to implement web 3 or work/research on it. They either get away with it or just delay the project until the forseeable future. The next category which I hate the most I call the &ldquo;leechers&rdquo;. They hype this thing up for their own financial benefits, NFT owners are a very large chunk of them, they simply want web 3 to get an increased value on their tokens without proper research/knowledge about the topic. You can read my previous post to see how that works.</p>
<p><strong>Second category:</strong>
They are engineers like you and me who are exsited about web3 as it brings new technologies and developments in this era. They follow a logic and have common sense.
Now when these enginners shows some interest publicly about this topic, the leechers usually follow up and hype this thing up to the moon. &ldquo;Hey Professor X said he likes web 3 idea of decentralization, SO BUY OUR NFTS TO SECURE A PLACE IN THE METAVERSE.&rdquo; and you know the rest and where the problem is coming from.</p>
<p>A proper company that manages to properly adapt web 3, work on it, squash the bugs and has a use for it for a good purpose are a the ones you should follow and look after. Research papers are a great start as well.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>NFTs are horrible</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2022/02/nfts-are-horrible/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2022/02/nfts-are-horrible/</guid>
            <description>I believe the NFT society would hate me but considering that twitter and YouTube are trying to enter this space, it&amp;rsquo;s worth to discuss it.
You can see a 2 hour video made by Folding Ideas about the topic which I strongly recommend, called Line Goes Up – The Problem With NFTs
Since the text is too long I will split it up to different sections.
Morality The whole concept of NFTs are buying something worthless and convincing someone to buy it at a higher price, the act itself carries 0 benefits (If not harm) for anyone.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I believe the NFT society would hate me but considering that twitter and YouTube are trying to enter this space, it&rsquo;s worth to discuss it.<br>
You can see a 2 hour video made by Folding Ideas about the topic which I strongly recommend, called <a href="https://youtu.be/YQ_xWvX1n9g">Line Goes Up – The Problem With NFTs</a><br>
Since the text is too long I will split it up to different sections.</p>
<h3 id="morality">Morality</h3>
<p>The whole concept of NFTs are buying something worthless and convincing someone to buy it at a higher price, the act itself carries 0 benefits (If not harm) for anyone. It just amplifies one charecteristic of humans, <strong>Greed</strong>. In a classic method of trade, when setting aside the money, the end-user either:</p>
<ul>
<li>Solves one of their problems (Let&rsquo;s say buying a tool like a hammer, car for transport etc..)</li>
<li>Gets food or a drink (Obvious reasons)</li>
<li>Enjoys their time (Going to a concert, watching a movie)</li>
<li>Learns something (Skill, Profession, Internship etc&hellip;)</li>
</ul>
<p>In comparison NFTs have only one motive &ldquo;MONEY&rdquo;, the seller, distributor, creator all are gathered just to make money.</p>
<h3 id="economics">Economics</h3>
<p>The whole NFT creation and the costs involved (Not to mention the transfer costs) are very inefficient. The amount of power the network draws does not make sense at all. Also do you know what happens when something which is not worth much is sold and bidded at a higher price brings? Inflation.</p>
<p>If NFTs get used by other big companies like meta and youtube, we will experience extreme inflation, as NFTs become part of their assets and the prices are falsely driven up (by biders or people who own nfts), it creates an illusion of increase in capital while in practice it&rsquo;s not worth that much at all which creates inflation</p>
<h3 id="security">Security</h3>
<p>You might say: &ldquo;Well at least it&rsquo;s decentralized&rdquo;, and I&rsquo;m here to tell you it&rsquo;s not when the item is listed on a public website which is being run on a centralized server in order to be traded. A simple centralized encrypted tocken is a hundered times more protected than this method also, don&rsquo;t forget screenshots.</p>
<h2 id="comparison-with-crypto">Comparison with crypto</h2>
<p>The things I mentioned has a lot in common with crypto which is the point which I start to disagree with the mentioned video. Despite their similarities, crypto is an attempt to solve transactions and bank fees. (even though not a good one)</p>
<p>A bank transaction from let&rsquo;s say US to Singapore involves multiple fees:</p>
<ul>
<li>Bank charges for international transfer</li>
<li>Intermediary bank charges</li>
<li>exchange fees</li>
<li>Transaction fees (sometimes)</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Transaction time? 1 to 3 days</em></p>
<p>Crypto fees (Bitcoin and Ethereum):</p>
<ul>
<li>one time fee of 10 ~ 20$</li>
</ul>
<p><em>transaction time? less than an hour</em><br>
Also this is in a good world which crypto is widely accepted and banks don&rsquo;t charge fees from withdrawing through exchanges.</p>
<p><strong>A better way</strong><br>
There is a better way to execute this, good attempts are already made by Wise and CurrencyFair, WorldRemit etc&hellip; which they execute by peer 2 peer transfers. let&rsquo;s say you live in singapore and want to transfer to US and someone in US wants to transfer to singapore. Each of you transfer locally to the other persons end account. Of course this is again when both of you want to transfer the same amount. Which the above platforms solve by finding a good match. So crypto, despite of it&rsquo;s innovation still lacks wide acceptability and stable price and is not good for small transactions, Moreover the other person should spend it in local currency which the banks come again and take a bite. So you are back to square 1.</p>
<p>All in all I think there are much bigger problems to solve at the moment rather than buying thousands of dollars of memes.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Wordpress Weaknesses</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2021/10/wordpress-weaknesses/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2021/10/wordpress-weaknesses/</guid>
            <description>After dealing with wordpress for 3 months, I come down to realize how crappy it is, a great example on what a project can become without a proper goal and heavy reliance on 3rd party code.
Free? (Not quite) Wordpress is free but it costs something more than money, time.
Even not considering the fact that most of the extensions will constantly bug you to buy their paid version. There is no standard for themes, or extensions or what sort of path they should follow.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After dealing with wordpress for 3 months, I come down to realize how crappy it is, a great example on what a project can become without a proper goal and heavy reliance on 3rd party code.</p>
<h3 id="free-not-quite">Free? (Not quite)</h3>
<p>Wordpress is free but it costs something more than money, <strong>time</strong>.<br>
Even not considering the fact that most of the extensions will constantly bug you to buy their paid version. There is no standard for themes, or extensions or what sort of path they should follow. Each creator sort of glues everything together and then releases it and calls it a day. So you have to look hours to change part of a text, or a variable that the creator forgot to include in settings and you have to manually search for it and edit it.</p>
<h3 id="slow">Slow</h3>
<p>Being slow is not something new, anything asociated with PHP will automatically get this feature for free. (Not that PHP is bad though, but wordpress is not optimized enough). A simple optimization and security testing is something every dev should do which is <strong>part of users RIGHTS</strong>, unless you are providing it as a beta and in a small scale form.<br>
I&rsquo;ve done improvements from gziping all the packages, minifying the code, avoiding heavy pictures etc&hellip; but it&rsquo;s not as smooth as other proper websites.</p>
<h3 id="plugins-plugins-and-plugins">Plugins, Plugins and Plugins!</h3>
<p>For the most basic tasks you will need a plugin, a simple reset function requires a pluging, contact form is a pluging, SMTP for managing emails is a plugin, website migration is a plugin, and it continues. The devs could&rsquo;ve at least copy-pasted some plugings in the core project.<br>
This modularity automatically brings exploits, each plugin introduces a new exploit and then you are in trouble.</p>
<h3 id="open-source-morals">Open-source Morals</h3>
<p>Why didn&rsquo;t I write this as Open source <em>rules</em>? because it doesn&rsquo;t contradict any. Morally open source projects should allow direct access of everything and take money for support or premium plans <strong>if you wish</strong> and not poke it into your eye everytime you install a plugin or a demo theme. This is not on devs but rather on the community.</p>
<h3 id="solutions">Solutions?</h3>
<p>As a felow smol web dev, I will still recommend it for small sites that don&rsquo;t need extensions that much, but for anything beyond that avoiding it seems the best solution. I wrote this website of mine as a static page, it is not as good looking but it&rsquo;s both fast, reliable and almost non-hackable.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Google Code-in</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2019/12/google-code-in/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2019/12/google-code-in/</guid>
            <description>The Journey It goes back all the way in November when Fedora Project tweeted that they need some Mentors for Google Code-in. Initially I didn&amp;rsquo;t knew what it was but after a simple search it was clear that it was a competition ran by Google.
So Google provided all the backend and platform for open source organizations, which mentors of each org then creates tasks in the system, which then the student solves.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/photo/codein.png" alt="main page" title="Main page"></p>
<h2 id="the-journey">The Journey</h2>
<p>It goes back all the way in November when Fedora Project tweeted that they need some Mentors for Google Code-in. Initially I didn&rsquo;t knew what it was but after a simple search it was clear that it was a competition ran by Google.<br>
<br>
So Google provided all the backend and platform for open source organizations, which mentors of each org then creates tasks in the system, which then the student solves. At the end students will be rewarded goodies all supplied by Google.<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/codein2.jpg" alt="Short Description">
<br>
It was clear that Google wants to be viewed as open-source supporter and get some love from the students, then also hiring talented ones, so Google gets a big piece here. (Although Open-source orgs can show their stuff too but much less compared to Google)<br>
<br>
See some info <a href="https://opensource.google/community/">here</a></p>
<h2 id="getting-chosen">Getting chosen</h2>
<p>Well after filling the simple form I was contacted by Vipul, the event manager that I should hand some draft tasks for him to analyse so I kept working and used my Internship Knowledge to create some server tasks, which was accepted by Vipul and I was in.<br>
After a while we were given the link to register as mentor and deploy our tasks with markdown, everythign was straight forward and documented</p>
<p><img src="/img/photo/codein3.jpg" alt="My tasks"></p>
<h2 id="competition">Competition</h2>
<p>Initially Studnts grabbed and then abandoned my tasks, which I was told that this is regular because they are getting familiar with the UI.<br>
<br>
After reviewing some submissions I was worried that the tasks are way to easy, so I removed some Documentation tasks to minimize spams. Then Created LaTeX and NextCloud ones instead, which students loved.<br>
<br>
After a week the submission amount was enormus, I got 50 ish tasks to review everyday, it was convenient and boring at the same time.<br>
<br>
We had some conferences at the end to choose the winners with other mentors, and after announcing winners and runner-ups, the event was ended.<br>
<br>
The only student form my Area (UAE, Dubai) actually won the first place, but never went to the Google Headquarters because of the Covid-19 pandemic. (Believe me it is very sad.)</p>
<h2 id="what-i-got">What I got</h2>
<p><br>
<strong>My Goodies aren&rsquo;t shipped yet this is what we are &ldquo;supposed&rdquo; to get</strong><br>
<br>
<img src="https://prajwalpatiltech.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/img_20170222_161114-e1487761420101.jpg?w=775" alt="rewards"><br>
<br>
Well Physically: certificate and a T-shirt but the most important ones are friends and the experience which will top everything here.</p>
<p><a href="https://codein.withgoogle.com">check the website</a><br>
<a href="https://medium.com/@p4r4xor/my-journey-at-google-code-in-paraxor-8492c4b15eda">paraxor&rsquo;s awesome event description for students</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Robocup Asia-Pacific @ Dubai</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</guid>
            <description>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects. The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced
was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects.
<br>
<br>
The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX. My team was elected to participate, since we have done the fastest lap by combining ultrasonic sensivity and follow the line sensors. (It was quite easy since we used a graphical user interface to program the virtual robots, which then translated into C++ code that the virtual bot executed.
<br>
<br>
You can see some useful info in <a href="http://robocupap.org/index.php/dubai2018/">Event Website</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6KHG87fK4LE">Event video</a>.
<br>
We won the election process and went for the master competition held in Dubai Knowledge village.
<br>
<br>
The beginning of the event was easy since it was quite similar to what our school trained us for but the final levels were quite hard as the code should both run on the Physical and Virtual robot which was quite scary as sometimes the one that worked on the virtual bot didn&rsquo;t work on physical and vice versa.
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo.jpg" alt="menu">
<br>
After lots of challenge our team <em>Pioneers</em> got the first place in U19 challenge which was quite nice, although we asked why the code gave different results on Physical and Virual, the company supplier told us that in order to make the virtual section more challenging they assigned some random values to initial velocity which gave weird results everytime in return. Some fine shots can be seen here:
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo2.jpg" alt="menu">
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo3.jpg" alt="menu"></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
